# **Navid Mashinchi**

nmashinchi@gmail.com | 916-330-0268 | Irvine, CA | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **SUMMARY**

Results-driven data professional with 5+ years of experience. Currently working as a Data Scientist I at Kohl's and Adjunct Professor at the University of Denver. Recognized with the KDnuggets Silver Blog and Streamlit New User of the Month awards.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Data Scientist I, Kohl's, Remote

June 2022 – Present

**Product Recommendations:** 

• Currently leading the development of a hybrid matrix factorization model utilizing LightFM, BigQuery, Kubeflow, and Vertex AI to provide more personalized recommendations on the e-commerce platform of Kohl's.com.

#### Supply Chain:

- Implemented a production-ready LightGBM Model using Vertex AI and BigQuery to predict inventory item arrival at the United States Port of Entries, resulting in a mean absolute error of 6 days for inferences made six months in advance of purchase order approval.
- Modularized notebook code into Python scripts and Kubeflow components by using functional programming to successfully deploy prototype model into production.
- Developed a real-time performance monitoring dashboard using Streamlit, enabling continuous tracking and assessment of the model's performance in the production environment.

#### **Associate Data Scientist**, Kohl's, *Remote*

September 2021 – June 2022

- Promoted within ten months for exceeding goals from Associate Data Scientist to Data Scientist I.
- Developed machine learning models in Python using data stored in MongoDB for the Supply Chain team to predict when inventory will arrive at particular supply chain journey segments to provide merchants and logistics teams with better information for planning purposes.
- Optimized the ML models by hyper-parameter tuning using Optuna.
- Data visualization using Seaborn and Matplotlib to better deduce results on sampled data.

#### **Adjunct Professor**, University of Denver, *Remote*

June 2022 – Present

- Currently lecture graduate students enrolled in Database Organization and Management I.
- Provide office hours for graduate students to answer questions regarding course materials.
- Other courses taught: Machine Learning.

#### Lead Analyst, Vancouver Whitecaps FC, Vancouver, BC, Canada

June 2016 – February 2018

- Managed the analytics department, consisting of one full-time analyst and three interns after losing the supervisor without a drop-in output by providing consistent analytical services to the staff, players, and senior leadership resulting in reaching the MLS playoffs.
- Created 34+ analytical reports on the opposition through data collection and uncovering patterns and trends for the MLS coaching staff.
- Presented research findings to coaches weekly and wrote requested summaries detailing the department's state to senior leadership.

Assistant Analyst, Vancouver Whitecaps FC, Vancouver, BC, Canada

January 2015 – May 2016

- Supported the department head by analyzing future opposition through statistical and video analysis.
- Collected and analyzed data on prospective incoming players to help the club make better decisions on player acquisitions.
- Led a team of three interns, trained them on the department's operations procedures, resulting in one full-time hire.

## **EDUCATION & AWARDS**

Master's in Data Science, University of Denver, Denver, CO. USA

August 2021

• GPA: 3.92/4.00

Bachelor of Commerce, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

December 2015

• Specialization: Accounting

#### KDnuggets Silver Blog - March Award, Award Link

April 2021

• Earned the KDnuggets Silver Blog March award for having over 9000 views for my article: "The Portfolio Guide for Data Science Beginners".

#### Streamlit New User of the Month Award, Award Link

March 2021

• Earned the new user of the month award for my COVID-19 dashboard (web app) and articles that I shared.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, R, JavaScript.
- Data Science: Data Cleaning & Wrangling (Pandas, NumPy), Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Folium, Geoplot, Ggplot2), Big Data (Spark), Statistics, Hypothesis Testing, Modeling, Interpretation.
- Machine Learning: Scikit-Learn, Supervised ML, Unsupervised ML, TensorFlow, Keras.
- Databases & Others: SQL, MongoDB, Relational Algebra, ER Modeling, GitHub, Git, Streamlit, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Node.JS, Google Cloud Platform, Vertex AI, Kubeflow.